<hack-root xmlns="http://cnx.rice.edu/cnxml">
  <!-- START:Chapter -->
  <!-- START:Page -->
  <!-- Markup starts here -->
  <note class="history defining-american">
    <label>Defining American</label>
    <title>Columbus's <emphasis effect="italics">Probanza de m'rito</emphasis> of 1493</title>
    <para>The exploits of the most famous Spanish explorers have provided Western civilization with a narrative of European supremacy and Indian savagery. However, these stories are based on the self-aggrandizing efforts of conquistadors to secure royal favor through the writing of <emphasis effect="italics">probanzas de m'ritos</emphasis> (proofs of merit). Below are excerpts from Columbus's 1493 letter to Luis de Sant'ngel, which illustrates how fantastic reports from European explorers gave rise to many myths surrounding the Spanish conquest and the New World.</para>
    <para>
      <quote>This island, like all the others, is most extensive. It has many ports along the sea-coast excelling any in Christendom and many fine, large, flowing rivers. The land there is elevated, with many mountains and peaks incomparably higher than in the centre isle. They are most beautiful, of a thousand varied forms, accessible, and full of trees of endless varieties, so high that they seem to touch the sky, and I have been told that they never lose their foliage. . . . There is honey, and there are many kinds of birds, and a great variety of fruits. Inland there are numerous mines of metals and innumerable people. Hispaniola is a marvel. Its hills and mountains, fine plains and open country, are rich and fertile for planting and for pasturage, and for building towns and villages. The seaports there are incredibly fine, as also the magnificent rivers, most of which bear gold. The trees, fruits and grasses differ widely from those in Juana. There are many spices and vast mines of gold and other metals in this island. They have no iron, nor steel, nor weapons, nor are they fit for them, because although they are well-made men of commanding stature, they appear extraordinarily timid. The only arms they have are sticks of cane, cut when in seed, with a sharpened stick at the end, and they are afraid to use these. Often I have sent two or three men ashore to some town to converse with them, and the natives came out in great numbers, and as soon as they saw our men arrive, fled without a moment's delay although I protected them from all injury.</quote>
    </para>
    <para>What does this letter show us about Spanish objectives in the New World? How do you think it might have influenced Europeans reading about the New World for the first time?</para>
  </note>
  <!-- END:Page -->
  <!-- END:Chapter -->
</hack-root>
