<hack-root xmlns="http://cnx.rice.edu/cnxml">
  <!-- START:Chapter -->
  <!-- START:Page -->
  <!-- Markup starts here -->
  <note class="microbiology disease-profile">
    <title>Mycoses of the Skin</title>
    <para>Cutaneous mycoses are typically opportunistic, only able to cause infection when the skin barrier is breached through a wound. Tineas are the exception, as the dermatophytes responsible for tineas are able to grow on skin, hair, and nails, especially in moist conditions. Most mycoses of the skin can be avoided through good hygiene and proper wound care. Treatment requires antifungal medications. <link target-id="OSC_Microbio_21_04_DMycoses"/> summarizes the characteristics of some common fungal infections of the skin.</para>
    <figure>
      <media alt="Table titled: Mycoses of the Skin. Columns: Disease, Pathogen, Signs and Symptoms, Transmission, Antimicrobial Drugs. Aspergillosis (cutaneous), Aspergillus fumigatus, Aspergillus flavus, Distinctive eschars at site(s) of infection, Entry via wound (primary cutaneous aspergillosis) or via the respiratory system (secondary cutaneous aspergillosis); commonly a hospital-acquired infection, Itraconazole, voriconazole, amphotericin B. Candidiasis (cutaneous), Candida albicans, Intertrigo, localized rash, yellowing of nails, Opportunistic infections in immunocompromised patients, Azoles. Sporotrichosis (rose gardeners disease), Sporothrix schenkii, Subcutaneous ulcers and abscesses; may spread to a large area, e.g., hand or arm, Entry via thorn prick or other wound, Itraconazole. Tineas, Trichophyton spp., Epidermophyton spp., Microsporum spp., Itchy, ring-like lesions (ringworm) at sites of infection, Contact with dermatophytic fungi, especially in warm, moist environments conducive to fungal growth, Terbinafine, miconazole, clotrimazole, griseofulvin.">
        <image mime-type="image/jpeg" src="OSC_Microbio_21_04_DMycoses.jpg"/>
      </media>
    </figure>
  </note>
  <!-- END:Page -->
  <!-- END:Chapter -->
</hack-root>
