<hack-root xmlns="http://cnx.rice.edu/cnxml">
  <!-- START:Chapter -->
  <!-- START:Page -->
  <!-- Markup starts here -->
  <note class="microbiology case-in-point">
    <title>An Unwelcome Anaerobe</title>
    <para>Charles is a retired bus driver who developed type 2 <term class="no-emphasis">diabetes</term> over 10 years ago. Since his retirement,his lifestyle has become very sedentary and he has put on a substantial amount of weight. Although he has felt tingling and numbness in his left foot for a while, he has not been worried because he thought his foot was simply falling asleep. Recently, a scratch on his foot does not seem to be healing and is becoming increasingly ugly. Because the sore did not bother him much, Charles figured it could not be serious until his daughter noticed a purplish discoloration spreading on the skin and oozing (<link target-id="OSC_Microbio_09_02_foot"/>). When he was finally seen by his physician, Charles was rushed to the operating room. His open sore, or ulcer, is the result of a <term class="no-emphasis">diabetic foot</term>.</para>
    <para>The concern here is that <term class="no-emphasis">gas gangrene</term> may have taken hold in the dead tissue. The most likely agent of gas gangrene is <term class="no-emphasis"><emphasis effect="italics">Clostridium perfringens</emphasis></term>, an endospore-forming, gram-positive bacterium. It is an obligate anaerobe that grows in tissue devoid of oxygen. Since dead tissue is no longer supplied with oxygen by the circulatory system, the dead tissue provides pockets of ideal environment for the growth of <emphasis>C. perfringens</emphasis>.</para>
    <para>A surgeon examines the ulcer and radiographs of Charles foot and determines that the bone is not yet infected. The wound will have to be surgically debrided (debridement refers to the removal of dead and infected tissue) and a sample sent for microbiological lab analysis, but Charles will not have to have his foot amputated. Many diabetic patients are not so lucky. In 2008, nearly 70,000 diabetic patients in the United States lost a foot or limb to amputation, according to statistics from the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.<footnote>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. Living With Diabetes: Keep Your Feet Healthy. http://www.cdc.gov/Features/DiabetesFootHealth/</footnote></para>
    <list>
      <item>Which growth conditions would you recommend for the detection of <emphasis>C. perfringens</emphasis>?</item>
    </list>
    <figure>
      <media alt="A swollen foot with peeling skin and black regions under the skin.">
        <image mime-type="image/jpeg" src="OSC_Microbio_09_02_foot.jpg"/>
      </media>
      <caption>This clinical photo depicts ulcers on the foot of a diabetic patient. Dead tissue accumulating in ulcers can provide an ideal growth environment for the anaerobe <emphasis>C. perfringens</emphasis>, a causative agent of gas gangrene. (credit: Shigeo Kono, Reiko Nakagawachi, Jun Arata, Benjamin A Lipsky)</caption>
    </figure>
  </note>
  <!-- END:Page -->
  <!-- END:Chapter -->
</hack-root>
