<hack-root xmlns="http://cnx.rice.edu/cnxml">
  <!-- START:Chapter -->
  <!-- START:Page -->
  <!-- Markup starts here -->
  <note class="microbiology eye-on-ethics">
    <title>Microscopy and Antibiotic Resistance</title>
    <para>As the use of antibiotics has proliferated in medicine, as well as agriculture, microbes have evolved to become more resistant. Strains of bacteria such as methicillin-resistant <emphasis>S. aureus</emphasis> (<term class="no-emphasis">MRSA</term>), which has developed a high level of resistance to many antibiotics, are an increasingly worrying problem, so much so that research is underway to develop new and more diversified antibiotics.</para>
    <para>Fluorescence microscopy can be useful in testing the effectiveness of new antibiotics against resistant strains like MRSA. In a test of one new antibiotic derived from a marine bacterium, MC21-A (bromophene), researchers used the fluorescent dye <term class="no-emphasis">SYTOX Green</term> to stain samples of MRSA. SYTOX Green is often used to distinguish dead cells from living cells, with fluorescence microscopy. Live cells will not absorb the dye, but cells killed by an antibiotic will absorb the dye, since the antibiotic has damaged the bacterial cell membrane. In this particular case, MRSA bacteria that had been exposed to MC21-A did, indeed, appear green under the fluorescence microscope, leading researchers to conclude that it is an effective antibiotic against MRSA.</para>
    <para>Of course, some argue that developing new antibiotics will only lead to even more antibiotic-resistant microbes, so-called <term class="no-emphasis">superbugs</term> that could spawn epidemics before new treatments can be developed. For this reason, many health professionals are beginning to exercise more discretion in prescribing antibiotics. Whereas antibiotics were once routinely prescribed for common illnesses without a definite diagnosis, doctors and hospitals are much more likely to conduct additional testing to determine whether an antibiotic is necessary and appropriate before prescribing.</para>
    <para>A sick patient might reasonably object to this stingy approach to prescribing antibiotics. To the patient who simply wants to feel better as quickly as possible, the potential benefits of taking an antibiotic may seem to outweigh any immediate health risks that might occur if the antibiotic is ineffective. But at what point do the risks of widespread antibiotic use supersede the desire to use them in individual cases?</para>
  </note>
  <!-- END:Page -->
  <!-- END:Chapter -->
</hack-root>
