<hack-root xmlns="http://cnx.rice.edu/cnxml">
  <!-- START:Chapter -->
  <!-- START:Page -->
  <!-- Markup starts here -->
  <div class="sociology-real-world" data-has-label="true" data-label="" data-type="note">
    <div data-type="title">Overcoming Culture Shock</div>
    <p>During her summer vacation, Caitlin flew from Chicago to Madrid to visit Maria, the exchange student she&#x2019;d befriended the previous semester. In the airport, she heard rapid, musical Spanish being spoken all around her. Exciting as it was, she felt isolated and disconnected. Maria&#x2019;s mother kissed Caitlin on both cheeks when she greeted her. Her imposing father kept his distance. Caitlin was half asleep by the time supper was served&#x2014;at 10 p.m.! Maria&#x2019;s family sat at the table for hours, speaking loudly, gesturing, and arguing about politics, a taboo dinner subject in Caitlin&#x2019;s house. They served wine and toasted their honored guest. Caitlin had trouble interpreting her hosts&#x2019; facial expressions, and didn&#x2019;t realize she should make the next toast. That night, Caitlin crawled into a strange bed, wishing she hadn&#x2019;t come. She missed her home and felt overwhelmed by the new customs, language, and surroundings. She&#x2019;d studied Spanish in school for years&#x2014;why hadn&#x2019;t it prepared her for this?</p>
    <p>What Caitlin hadn&#x2019;t realized was that people depend not only on spoken words but also on subtle cues like gestures and facial expressions, to communicate. Cultural norms accompany even the smallest nonverbal signals (DuBois 1951). They help people know when to shake hands, where to sit, how to converse, and even when to laugh. We relate to others through a shared set of cultural norms, and ordinarily, we take them for granted.</p>
    <p>For this reason, culture shock is often associated with traveling abroad, although it can happen in one&#x2019;s own country, state, or even hometown. Anthropologist Kalervo Oberg (1960) is credited with first coining the term &#x201C;culture shock.&#x201D; In his studies, Oberg found that most people found encountering a new culture to be exciting at first. But bit by bit, they became stressed by interacting with people from a different culture who spoke another language and used different regional expressions. There was new food to digest, new daily schedules to follow, and new rules of etiquette to learn. Living with this constant stress can make people feel incompetent and insecure. People react to frustration in a new culture, Oberg found, by initially rejecting it and glorifying one&#x2019;s own culture. An American visiting Italy might long for a &#x201C;real&#x201D; pizza or complain about the unsafe driving habits of Italians compared to people in the United States.</p>
  </div>
  <!-- END:Page -->
  <!-- END:Chapter -->
</hack-root>
