<hack-root xmlns="http://cnx.rice.edu/cnxml">
  <!-- START:Chapter -->
  <!-- START:Page -->
  <!-- Markup starts here -->
  <note class="sociology-real-world">
    <label/>
    <title>The Woman Who Lives without Money</title>
    <para>Imagine having no money. If you wanted some french fries, needed a new pair of shoes, or were due to get an oil change for your car, how would you get those goods and services?</para>
    <para>This isn&#x2019;t just a theoretical question. Think about it. What do those on the outskirts of society do in these situations? Think of someone escaping domestic abuse who gave up everything and has no resources. Or an immigrant who wants to build a new life but who had to leave another life behind to find that opportunity. Or a homeless person who simply wants a meal to eat.</para>
    <para>This last example, homelessness, is what caused Heidemarie Schwermer to give up money. She was a divorced high school teacher in Germany, and her life took a turn when she relocated her children to a rural town with a significant homeless population. She began to question what serves as currency in a society and decided to try something new.</para>
    <para>Schwermer founded a business called <emphasis effect="italics">Gib und Nimm</emphasis>&#x2014;in English, &#x201C;give and take.&#x201D; It operated on a moneyless basis and strived to facilitate people swapping goods and services for other goods and services&#x2014;no cash allowed (Schwermer 2007). What began as a short experiment has become a new way of life. Schwermer says the change has helped her focus on people&#x2019;s inner value instead of their outward wealth. She wrote two books that tell her story (she&#x2019;s donated all proceeds to charity) and, most importantly, a richness in her life she was unable to attain with money. </para>
    <para>How might our three sociological perspectives view her actions? What would most interest them about her unconventional ways? Would a functionalist consider her aberration of norms a social dysfunction that upsets the normal balance? How would a conflict theorist place her in the social hierarchy? What might a symbolic interactionist make of her choice not to use money&#x2014;such an important symbol in the modern world?</para>
    <para>What do <emphasis effect="italics">you</emphasis> make of <emphasis effect="italics">Gib und Nimm</emphasis>?</para>
  </note>
  <!-- END:Page -->
  <!-- END:Chapter -->
</hack-root>
