<hack-root xmlns="http://cnx.rice.edu/cnxml">
  <!-- START:Chapter -->
  <!-- START:Page -->
  <!-- Markup starts here -->
  <para>If free riding is so prevalent, why are there so many interest groups and why is interest group membership so high in the United States? One reason is that free riding can be overcome in a variety of ways. Olson argued, for instance, that some groups are better able than others to surmount collective action problems.<cite target-id="rf-018"><note class="reference" display="inline" id="rf-018">Olson, Jr., <emphasis effect="italics">The Logic of Collective Action</emphasis>.</note></cite> They can sometimes maintain themselves by obtaining financial support from patrons outside the group.<cite target-id="rf-019"><note class="reference" display="inline" id="rf-019">Jack Walker, &#x201C;The Origin and Maintenance of Interest Groups in America,&#x201D; <emphasis effect="italics">American Political Science Review</emphasis> 77 (1983): 390&#x2013;406.</note></cite> Groups with financial resources have an advantage in mobilizing in that they can offer incentives or hire a lobbyist. Smaller, well-organized groups also have an advantage. For one thing, opinions within smaller groups may be more similar, making it easier to reach consensus. It is also more difficult for members to free ride in a smaller group. In comparison, larger groups have a greater number of individuals and therefore more viewpoints to consider, making consensus more difficult. It may also be easier to free ride because it is less obvious in a large group when any single person does not contribute. However, if people do not lobby for their own interests, they may find that they are ignored, especially if smaller but more active groups with interests opposed to theirs lobby on behalf of themselves. Even though the United States is a democracy, policy is often made to suit the interests of the few instead of the needs of the many.</para>
  <!-- END:Page -->
  <!-- END:Chapter -->
</hack-root>
