<hack-root xmlns="http://cnx.rice.edu/cnxml">
  <!-- START:Chapter -->
  <!-- START:Page -->
  <!-- Markup starts here -->
  <note class="insider-perspective">
    <title>Inside the Debate</title>
    <para>Debating an opponent in front of sixty million television voters is intimidating. Most presidential candidates spend days, if not weeks, preparing. Newspapers and cable news programs proclaim winners and losers, and debates can change the tide of a campaign. Yet, Paul <term class="no-emphasis">Begala</term>, a strategist with Bill Clinton&#x2019;s 1992 campaign, saw debates differently.</para>
    <para>In one of his columns for CNN, Begala recommends that candidates relax and have a little fun. Debates are relatively easy, he says, more like a scripted program than an interview that puts candidates on the spot. They can memorize answers and deliver them convincingly, making sure they hit their mark. Second, a candidate needs a clear message explaining why the voters should pick him or her. Is he or she a needed change? Or the only experienced candidate? If the candidate&#x2019;s debate answers reinforce this message, the voters will remember. Third, candidates should be humorous, witty, and comfortable with their knowledge. Trying to be too formal or cramming information at the last minute will cause the candidate to be awkward or get overwhelmed. Finally, a candidate is always on camera. Making faces, sighing at an opponent, or simply making a mistake gives the media something to discuss and can cause a loss. In essence, Begala argues that if candidates wish to do well, preparation and confidence are key factors.<cite target-id="rf-89"><note class="reference" display="inline" id="rf-89">Paul Begala. 1 October 2008. &#x201C;Commentary: 10 Rules for Winning a Debate,&#x201D; http://www.cnn.com/2008/POLITICS/10/01/begala.debate/index.html?iref=24hours.</note></cite></para>
    <para>
      <emphasis effect="italics">Is Begala&#x2019;s advice good? Why or why not? What positives or negatives would make a candidate&#x2019;s debate performance stand out for you as a voter?</emphasis>
    </para>
  </note>
  <!-- END:Page -->
  <!-- END:Chapter -->
</hack-root>
