<hack-root xmlns="http://cnx.rice.edu/cnxml">
  <!-- START:Chapter -->
  <!-- START:Page -->
  <!-- Markup starts here -->
    <note id="fs-id1168047608352" class="astronomy voyagers-in-astronomy">
      <title>George Darwin and the Slowing of Earth</title>
      <para id="fs-id1168047125156">The rubbing of water over the face of Earth involves an enormous amount of energy. Over long periods of time, the friction of the tides is slowing down the rotation of Earth. Our day gets longer by about 0.002 second each century. That seems very small, but such tiny changes can add up over millions and billions of years.</para>
      <para id="fs-id1168047640964">Although Earth&#8217;s spin is slowing down, the angular momentum (see <link class="target-chapter" document="m59773">Orbits and Gravity</link>) in a system such as the Earth-Moon system cannot change. Thus, some other spin motion must speed up to take the extra angular momentum. The details of what happens were worked out over a century ago by George <term class="no-emphasis">Darwin</term>, the son of naturalist Charles Darwin. George Darwin (see <link target-id="OSC_Astro_04_06_Darwin"/>) had a strong interest in science but studied law for six years and was admitted to the bar. However, he never practiced law, returning to science instead and eventually becoming a professor at Cambridge University. He was a prot&#233;g&#233; of Lord Kelvin, one of the great physicists of the nineteenth century, and he became interested in the long-term evolution of the solar system. He specialized in making detailed (and difficult) mathematical calculations of how orbits and motions change over geologic time.</para>
      <figure id="OSC_Astro_04_06_Darwin">
      <title>George Darwin (1845&#8211;1912).</title>
      <media id="fs-id1168047570594" alt="Photograph of George Darwin.">
      <image mime-type="image/jpeg" src="OSC_Astro_04_06_Darwin.jpg"/>
      </media>
      <caption>George Darwin is best known for studying Earth&#8217;s spin in relation to angular momentum.</caption>
      </figure>
      <para id="fs-id1168047721578">What Darwin calculated for the Earth-Moon system was that the Moon will slowly spiral outward, away from Earth. As it moves farther away, it will orbit less quickly (just as planets farther from the Sun move more slowly in their orbits). Thus, the month will get longer. Also, because the Moon will be more distant, total eclipses of the Sun will no longer be visible from Earth.</para>
      <para id="fs-id1168047567835">Both the day and the month will continue to get longer, although bear in mind that the effects are very gradual. Darwin&#8217;s calculations were confirmed by mirrors placed on the Moon by Apollo 11 astronauts. These show that the Moon is moving away by 3.8 centimeters per year, and that ultimately&#8212;billions of years in the future&#8212;the day and the month will be the same length (about 47 of our present days). At this point the Moon will be stationary in the sky over the same spot on Earth, meaning some parts of Earth will see the Moon and its phases and other parts will never see them. This kind of alignment is already true for Pluto&#8217;s moon Charon (among others). Its rotation and orbital period are the same length as a day on Pluto.</para>
    </note>
  <!-- END:Page -->
  <!-- END:Chapter -->
</hack-root>