<hack-root xmlns="http://cnx.rice.edu/cnxml">
  <!-- START:Chapter -->
  <!-- START:Page -->
  <!-- Markup starts here -->
  <div class="think-through" data-type="note" id="auto_6a603a50-9f9d-4ed6-be67-ff5a0df5c68a_eip-id1171823986677"><div data-type="title" id="auto_6a603a50-9f9d-4ed6-be67-ff5a0df5c68a_13235">Daily Purchases</div><p id="auto_6a603a50-9f9d-4ed6-be67-ff5a0df5c68a_eip-id1171823986526">Consider purchasing toothpaste from your local drug store. The drug store purchases large quantities of toothpaste from a wholesale distributor. They may purchase tens of thousands of tubes of toothpaste to get a better per-tube cost. <a class="autogenerated-content" href="#auto_6a603a50-9f9d-4ed6-be67-ff5a0df5c68a_eip-id1171824142564">[link]</a> shows that they then add their mark-up (or profit) to the tube and offer it for sale to you, a single tube at a time. The drug store did not manufacture the toothpaste, instead they are reselling the toothpaste they acquired from the wholesaler. Virtually all your daily purchases are made from merchandising firms such as Walmart, Target, Macy’s, Walgreens, and AutoZone, to name just a few.</p>
  <figure id="auto_6a603a50-9f9d-4ed6-be67-ff5a0df5c68a_eip-id1171824142564"><figcaption>Figure caption goes here.</figcaption><span data-alt="Alt text placeholder." data-type="media" id="auto_6a603a50-9f9d-4ed6-be67-ff5a0df5c68a_eip-id1171823880746">

    <img alt="Alt text placeholder." data-media-type="image/png" id="auto_6a603a50-9f9d-4ed6-be67-ff5a0df5c68a_32925" src="../resources/3500bbd71f0d779688b64f28765914d3a4e25409"/>

  </span></figure>
  <p id="auto_6a603a50-9f9d-4ed6-be67-ff5a0df5c68a_eip-432">Consider purchasing toothpaste from your local drug store. The drug store purchases large quantities of toothpaste from a wholesale distributor. They may purchase tens of thousands of tubes of toothpaste to get a better per-tube cost. They then add their mark-up (or profit) to the tube and offer it for sale to you, a single tube at a time. The drug store (see <a class="autogenerated-content" href="#auto_6a603a50-9f9d-4ed6-be67-ff5a0df5c68a_eip-id1171823969042">[link]</a>) did not manufacture the toothpaste, instead they are reselling the toothpaste they acquired from the wholesaler. Virtually all your daily purchases are made from merchandising firms such as Walmart, Target, Macy’s, Walgreens, and AutoZone, to name just a few.</p><figure id="auto_6a603a50-9f9d-4ed6-be67-ff5a0df5c68a_eip-id1171823969042"><figcaption>Figure caption goes here.</figcaption><span data-alt="Alt text placeholder." data-type="media" id="auto_6a603a50-9f9d-4ed6-be67-ff5a0df5c68a_eip-id1171824002797">

    <img alt="Alt text placeholder." data-media-type="image/png" id="auto_6a603a50-9f9d-4ed6-be67-ff5a0df5c68a_45741" src="../resources/2ca456ee0d11c27799568c37ed760f4e9981ece1"/>

  </span></figure><p id="auto_6a603a50-9f9d-4ed6-be67-ff5a0df5c68a_eip-427">Consider purchasing toothpaste from your local drug store. The drug store purchases large quantities of toothpaste from a wholesale distributor. They may purchase tens of thousands of tubes of toothpaste to get a better per-tube cost. They then add their mark-up (or profit) to the tube and offer it for sale to you, a single tube at a time. The drug store did not manufacture the toothpaste, instead they are reselling the toothpaste they acquired from the wholesaler. Virtually all your daily purchases are made from merchandising firms such as Walmart, Target, Macy’s, Walgreens, and AutoZone, to name just a few. </p>
</div>
  <!-- END:Page -->
  <!-- END:Chapter -->
</hack-root>
