<hack-root xmlns="http://cnx.rice.edu/cnxml">
  <!-- START:Chapter -->
  <!-- START:Page -->
  <!-- Markup starts here -->
  <div class="your-turn" data-type="note" id="auto_df2cf28d-6144-41bf-b7c8-92ebc77942c1_eip-id1171824185146">
    <div data-type="title" id="auto_df2cf28d-6144-41bf-b7c8-92ebc77942c1_63368">Example Identifying Relevant Costs and Revenues with Ella Graham and Pampered Pooches Using the LIFO, FIFO and FASB Methods</div>
    <p id="auto_df2cf28d-6144-41bf-b7c8-92ebc77942c1_eip-id1171823943515">For the following scenario, identify any relevant costs, relevant revenues, sunk cost, and opportunity costs. </p>
    <p id="auto_df2cf28d-6144-41bf-b7c8-92ebc77942c1_eip-796">Ella Graham, is CEO of her own marketing firm. The firm recently moved from a strip mall in the suburbs and leased office space in a downtown building, making them firm&#x2019;s employees more accessible to clients. Two new clients are interested in using Ella&#x2019;s advertising services but both clients are in the same line of business making it possible for Ella to only represent one of the clients. Pampered Pooches wants to hire Ella&#x2019;s firm for a one-year contract which includes web, newspaper, radio and direct mail advertising. Pampered will pay $126,000 for these services. Ella estimates the cost of the services requested by Pampered Pooches, as $83,000. Delightful Dogs is interested in hiring Ella to produce mass mailings and web ads. Delightful will pay Ella $94,000 for these services and Ella estimates the cost of these services to be $47,000.</p>
    <div data-type="list" id="auto_df2cf28d-6144-41bf-b7c8-92ebc77942c1_eip-838">
      <div data-type="title" id="auto_df2cf28d-6144-41bf-b7c8-92ebc77942c1_19020">Solution</div>
      <ul>
        <li>Relevant Costs: The $83,000 and $47,000 that will be charged to each client.</li>
        <li>Relevant Revenues: $126,000 and $94,000 from each of the two possible contracts. </li>
        <li>Sunk Costs: The lease on the current building.</li>
        <li>Opportunity Costs: The opportunity cost of accepting the Pampered Pooches contract is not getting the Delightful Dogs contract and vice-versa.</li>
      </ul>
    </div>
  </div>
  <!-- END:Page -->
  <!-- END:Chapter -->
</hack-root>
