<hack-root xmlns="http://cnx.rice.edu/cnxml">
  <!-- START:Chapter -->
  <!-- START:Page -->
  <!-- Markup starts here -->
  <div class="real-world" data-type="note" id="auto_cedd79c5-9659-4fd7-aee7-eb203f8d6dd7_eip-id1164997725271">
    <p id="auto_cedd79c5-9659-4fd7-aee7-eb203f8d6dd7_eip-id1164995652286">From mid-May to July 2017, criminal hackers gained access to Equifax servers that resulted in the unauthorized access to personal information on nearly one-half the U.S. population. Executives in the organization sold off nearly $2 million of company stock after finding out about the hack in late July, weeks before the breach was publicly announced on September 7. </p>
    <span data-alt="Alt text placeholder." data-type="media" id="auto_cedd79c5-9659-4fd7-aee7-eb203f8d6dd7_eip-id1165000176371">
      <img alt="Alt text placeholder." data-media-type="image/png" id="auto_cedd79c5-9659-4fd7-aee7-eb203f8d6dd7_26824" src="../resources/cb437e4ed98d0543dcdbf8a258ba881204470b16"/>
    </span>
    <p id="auto_cedd79c5-9659-4fd7-aee7-eb203f8d6dd7_eip-446">The company&#x2019;s shares fell nearly 14% after the end of the day of trading after the announcement. To make amends, the company offered free credit monitoring and identity theft protection. But anyone who signed up for these services potentially waived their right to be part of a class-action lawsuit. Only after public outrage did Equifax make clear that the clause waiving a right to join a class-action lawsuit did not apply to the recent breach. On September 15, the company&#x2019;s Chief Information Officer and Chief Security retired. On September 26, the CEO resigned as well, days before he was called to testify in Congress about the incident. To date, dozens of lawsuits have been filed as a result of the incident. </p>
    <p id="auto_cedd79c5-9659-4fd7-aee7-eb203f8d6dd7_eip-388">
      <strong class="centered-text">What do you think?</strong>
    </p>
    <p id="auto_cedd79c5-9659-4fd7-aee7-eb203f8d6dd7_eip-311">KC notes that the line above should be centered.</p>
    <p id="auto_cedd79c5-9659-4fd7-aee7-eb203f8d6dd7_eip-78">What are your thoughts about the integrity of Equifax and its leadership team, given the fact that they waited six weeks to inform the public of the breach, and sold off nearly $2 million of company shares during this time?<sup><a href="#rf-040302" id="rf-040302-og">2</a></sup></p>
    <div data-type="list" id="auto_cedd79c5-9659-4fd7-aee7-eb203f8d6dd7_eip-907">
      <div data-type="title" id="auto_cedd79c5-9659-4fd7-aee7-eb203f8d6dd7_96138">
        <strong>Critical Thinking:</strong>
      </div>
      <ul>
        <li>What response should the Equifax leadership team given?</li>
        <li>How does public opinion about white-collar crimes differ from that of other types of crime? </li>
      </ul>
    </div>
  </div>
  <!-- END:Page -->
  <!-- END:Chapter -->
</hack-root>
