<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" data-type="chapter">
  <h1 data-type="document-title">Chapter Title</h1>
  <div data-type="page"><div data-type="document-title">Page Title</div>
    Normal book content goes here

<!-- Markup starts here -->
<div class="ethics-across" data-type="note" id="auto_cc72a344-4dcc-47cf-8c3d-c3bc8655bfa8_eip-id1165002473287"><div data-type="title" id="auto_cc72a344-4dcc-47cf-8c3d-c3bc8655bfa8_42633">Burgers and Advertising</div><figure id="auto_cc72a344-4dcc-47cf-8c3d-c3bc8655bfa8_eip-id1165002364525"><figcaption>Figure caption goes here. KC notes that this caption contains an <span class="no-emphasis" data-type="term">index term</span> to see how it works.</figcaption><span data-alt="Alt text placeholder." data-type="media" id="auto_cc72a344-4dcc-47cf-8c3d-c3bc8655bfa8_eip-id1165002138712"><img alt="Alt text placeholder." data-media-type="image/png" id="auto_cc72a344-4dcc-47cf-8c3d-c3bc8655bfa8_30615" src="../resources/6a62f871490465da77d88ee35a481e611dea6966"/></span></figure><p id="auto_cc72a344-4dcc-47cf-8c3d-c3bc8655bfa8_59453">What does it take to manufacture the sign outside the stadium? It starts with the production department requisitioning vinyl and ink from the raw materials inventory.  Once the raw materials are delivered to the production department, the product is considered work-in-process inventory. There, <span class="no-emphasis" data-type="term">direct labor</span> is used to place the material into the printer, align the computerized design, and have it printed on the vinyl.  The direct materials and direct labor are known and recorded on the job order cost sheet. When the Production Department has completed its work, the sign and the job order cost sheet are transferred to the Finishing Department.  This department requests wood for framing and grommets for attaching the sign from raw materials inventory.  This department adds direct labor, wood, and grommets to the already printed sign to finish it properly.  </p><div data-type="list" id="auto_cc72a344-4dcc-47cf-8c3d-c3bc8655bfa8_eip-741"><div data-type="title" id="auto_cc72a344-4dcc-47cf-8c3d-c3bc8655bfa8_74250"><strong>Critical Thinking:</strong></div><ul><li>Why is the total of all completed costs on the job order cost sheet equal to the total of finished goods inventory?</li>
<li>Why do the jobs remain in finished goods inventory until they are sold?</li>
</ul></div></div>
<!-- Markup ends here -->

  </div>
</div>
