<hack-root xmlns="http://cnx.rice.edu/cnxml">
  <!-- START:Chapter -->
  <!-- START:Page -->
  <!-- Markup starts here -->
<div class="what-would" data-type="note" id="auto_ae5cc4ae-334f-4b0a-8d21-d12dccea93f4_fs-id1165000091882"><div data-type="title" id="auto_ae5cc4ae-334f-4b0a-8d21-d12dccea93f4_96581">New Equipment Costs for Premier</div><p id="auto_ae5cc4ae-334f-4b0a-8d21-d12dccea93f4_fs-id1165000035215">Despite their desire to meet consumer demand, Premier must analyze the costs associated with this new equipment to determine if the benefits outweigh the costs in <a class="autogenerated-content" href="#auto_ae5cc4ae-334f-4b0a-8d21-d12dccea93f4_eip-id1164992001546">[link]</a>.</p><figure id="auto_ae5cc4ae-334f-4b0a-8d21-d12dccea93f4_eip-id1164992001546"><figcaption>Figure capiton goes here.</figcaption><span data-alt="Alt text placeholder." data-type="media" id="auto_ae5cc4ae-334f-4b0a-8d21-d12dccea93f4_eip-id1165002498007"><img alt="Alt text placeholder." data-media-type="image/png" id="auto_ae5cc4ae-334f-4b0a-8d21-d12dccea93f4_19294" src="../resources/407abb686b56a16cf518014f84903df494f034ca"/></span></figure><p id="auto_ae5cc4ae-334f-4b0a-8d21-d12dccea93f4_eip-212">AlexCo produces collapsible wagons that are popular with beachgoers, shoppers, gardeners, parents and tailgaters. Annual sales have been 100,000 wagons per year. The retail selling price of each wagon is $67.00. To date, AlexCo has produced each of the components used in making the wagons but has been approached by DAL, Inc. with an offer to provide the axle and wheel assembly for $18.75 per assembly. AlexCo’s cost to produce the axle and wheel assembly are: $9.00 in direct materials, $6.50 in direct labor, $3.57 in variable overhead and $2.50 in fixed overhead. 25% of the fixed overhead is avoidable if the assembly is produced by DAL. Should AlexCo continue to make the axle and wheel assembly or should it buy the assembly from DAL, Inc.?</p><div data-type="list" id="auto_ae5cc4ae-334f-4b0a-8d21-d12dccea93f4_eip-268"><div data-type="title" id="auto_ae5cc4ae-334f-4b0a-8d21-d12dccea93f4_86109">Critical Thinking: </div><ul><li>As a member of the urban planning commission, how will you convince all stakeholders, including developers, investors, customers, politicians, and citizens, that the cost of sustainable development is worth the price? You can’t just say “Believe Me”, you have to support your opinion with reasons based on thoughtful analysis.</li>
<li>What do you think of this critical thinking question?</li>
<li>As a member of the urban planning commission, how will you convince all stakeholders, including developers, investors, customers, politicians, and citizens, that the cost of sustainable development is worth the price? </li>
</ul></div></div>
<!-- END:Page -->
<!-- END:Chapter -->
</hack-root>
