<hack-root xmlns="http://cnx.rice.edu/cnxml">
  <!-- START:Chapter -->
  <!-- START:Page -->
  <!-- Markup starts here -->
  <section id="fs-idm86921680" class="references">
    <title>References</title>
    <para>American Board of Forensic Psychology. (2014). <emphasis effect="italics">Brochure</emphasis>. Retrieved from http://www.abfp.com/brochure.asp</para>
    <para>American Psychological Association. (2014). Retrieved from www.apa.org</para>
    <para>American Psychological Association. (2014). <emphasis effect="italics">Graduate training and career possibilities in exercise and sport psychology. </emphasis>Retrieved from http://www.apadivisions.org/division-47/about/resources/training.aspx?item=1</para>
    <para>American Psychological Association. (2011). <emphasis effect="italics">Psychology as a career. </emphasis>Retrieved from http://www.apa.org/education/undergrad/psych-career.aspx</para>
    <para>Ashliman, D. L. (2001). Cupid and Psyche. In <emphasis effect="italics">Folktexts: A library of folktales, folklore, fairy tales, and mythology. </emphasis>Retrieved from http://www.pitt.edu/~dash/cupid.html</para>
    <para>Betancourt, H.,   Lpez, S. R. (1993). The study of culture, ethnicity, and race in American psychology. <emphasis effect="italics">American Psychologist</emphasis>, <emphasis effect="italics">48</emphasis>, 629 637.</para>
    <para>Black, S. R., Spence, S. A.,   Omari, S. R. (2004). Contributions of African Americans to the field of psychology. <emphasis effect="italics">Journal of Black Studies</emphasis>, <emphasis effect="italics">35</emphasis>, 40 64.</para>
    <para>Bulfinch, T. (1855). <emphasis effect="italics">The age of fable: Or, stories of gods and heroes</emphasis>. Boston, MA: Chase, Nichols and Hill.</para>
    <para>Buss, D. M. (1989). Sex differences in human mate preferences: Evolutionary hypotheses tested in 37 cultures. <emphasis effect="italics">Behavioral and Brain Sciences</emphasis>, <emphasis effect="italics">12</emphasis>, 1 49.</para>
    <para>Carlson, N. R. (2013). <emphasis effect="italics">Physiology of Behavior</emphasis> (11th ed.). Boston, MA: Pearson.</para>
    <para>Confer, J. C., Easton, J. A., Fleischman, D. S., Goetz, C. D., Lewis, D. M. G., Perilloux, C.,   Buss, D. M. (2010). Evolutionary psychology. Controversies, questions, prospects, and limitations. <emphasis effect="italics">American Psychologist</emphasis>, <emphasis effect="italics">65</emphasis>, 100 126.</para>
    <para id="fs-idm43049856">Crawford, M.,   Marecek, J. (1989). Psychology reconstructs the female 1968 1988. <emphasis effect="italics">Psychology of Women Quarterly</emphasis>, <emphasis effect="italics">13</emphasis>, 147 165.</para>
    <para>Danziger, K. (1980). The history of introspection reconsidered. <emphasis effect="italics">Journal of the History of the Behavioral Sciences</emphasis>, <emphasis effect="italics">16</emphasis>, 241 262.</para>
    <para>Darwin, C. (1871). <emphasis effect="italics">The</emphasis> <emphasis effect="italics">descent of man and selection in relation to sex</emphasis>. London: John Murray.</para>
    <para>Darwin, C. (1872). <emphasis effect="italics">The expression of the emotions in man and animals</emphasis>. London: John Murray.</para>
    <para>DeAngelis, T. (2010). Fear not. <emphasis effect="italics">gradPSYCH Magazine</emphasis>,<emphasis effect="italics"> 8</emphasis>, 38.</para>
    <para>Department of Health and Human Services. (n.d.). Projected future growth of the older population. Retrieved from http://www.aoa.gov/Aging_Statistics/future_growth/future_growth.aspx#age</para>
    <para>Endler, J. A. (1986). <emphasis effect="italics">Natural Selection in the Wild</emphasis>. Princeton, NJ: Princeton University Press.</para>
    <para>Fogg, N. P., Harrington, P. E., Harrington, T. F.,   Shatkin, L. (2012). <emphasis effect="italics">College majors handbook with real career paths and payoffs</emphasis> (3rd ed.). St. Paul, MN: JIST Publishing.</para>
    <para>Franko, D. L., et al. (2012). Racial/ethnic differences in adults in randomized clinical trials of binge eating disorder. <emphasis effect="italics">Journal of Consulting and Clinical Psychology</emphasis>, <emphasis effect="italics">80</emphasis>, 186 195.</para>
    <para>Friedman, H. (2008), Humanistic and positive psychology: The methodological and epistemological divide. <emphasis effect="italics">The Humanistic Psychologist</emphasis>, <emphasis effect="italics">36</emphasis>, 113 126.</para>
    <para>Gordon, O. E. (1995). <emphasis effect="italics">A brief history of psychology. </emphasis>Retrieved from http://www.psych.utah.edu/gordon/Classes/Psy4905Docs/PsychHistory/index.html#maptop</para>
    <para>Greek Myths   Greek Mythology. (2014). <emphasis effect="italics">The myth of Psyche and Eros. </emphasis>Retrieved from http://www.greekmyths-greekmythology.com/psyche-and-eros-myth/</para>
    <para>Green, C. D. (2001). Classics in the history of psychology. Retrieved from http://psychclassics.yorku.ca/Krstic/marulic.htm</para>
    <para>Greengrass, M. (2004). 100 years of B.F. Skinner. <emphasis effect="italics">Monitor on Psychology</emphasis>, <emphasis effect="italics">35</emphasis>, 80.</para>
    <para>Halonen, J. S. (2011). <emphasis effect="italics">White paper: Are there too many psychology majors? </emphasis>Prepared for the Staff of the State University System of Florida Board of Governors. Retrieved from http://www.cogdop.org/page_attachments/0000/0200/FLA_White_Paper_for_cogop_posting.pdf</para>
    <para>Hock, R. R. (2009). Social psychology. <emphasis effect="italics">Forty studies that changed psychology: Explorations into the history of psychological research</emphasis> (pp. 308 317). Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson.</para>
    <para>Hoffman, C. (2012). <emphasis effect="italics">Careers in clinical, counseling, or school psychology; mental health counseling; clinical social work; marriage   family therapy and related professions</emphasis>. Retrieved from http://www.indiana.edu/~psyugrad/advising/docs/Careers%20in%20Mental%20Health%20Counseling.pdf</para>
    <para>Jang, K. L., Livesly, W. J.,   Vernon, P. A. (1996). Heritability of the Big Five personality dimensions and their facets: A twin study. <emphasis effect="italics">Journal of Personality</emphasis>,<emphasis effect="italics"> 64</emphasis>, 577 591.</para>
    <para>Johnson, R.,   Lubin, G. (2011). College exposed: What majors are most popular, highest paying and most likely to get you a job. <emphasis effect="italics">Business Insider.com.</emphasis> Retrieved from http://www.businessinsider.com/best-college-majors-highest-income-most-employed-georgetwon-study-2011-6?op=1</para>
    <para>Knekt, P. P., et al. (2008). Randomized trial on the effectiveness of long- and short-term psychodynamic psychotherapy and solution-focused therapy on psychiatric symptoms during a 3-year follow-up. <emphasis effect="italics">Psychological Medicine: A Journal of Research In Psychiatry And The Allied Sciences</emphasis>, <emphasis effect="italics">38</emphasis>, 689 703.</para>
    <para>Landers, R. N. (2011, June 14). Grad school: Should I get a PhD or Master s in I/O psychology? [Web log post]. Retrieved from http://neoacademic.com/2011/06/14/grad-school-should-i-get-a-ph-d-or-masters-in-io-psychology/#.UuKKLftOnGg</para>
    <para>Macdonald, C. (2013). <emphasis effect="italics">Health psychology center presents: What is health psychology?</emphasis> Retrieved from http://healthpsychology.org/what-is-health-psychology/</para>
    <para>McCrae, R. R.   Costa, P. T. (2008). Empirical and theoretical status of the five-factor model of personality traits. In G. J. Boyle, G. Matthews,   D. H. Saklofske (Eds.), <emphasis effect="italics">The Sage handbook of personality theory and assessment. Vol. 1 Personality theories and models</emphasis>. London: Sage.</para>
    <para>Michalski, D., Kohout, J., Wicherski, M.,   Hart, B. (2011). <emphasis effect="italics">2009 Doctorate Employment Survey</emphasis>. APA Center for Workforce Studies. Retrieved from http://www.apa.org/workforce/publications/09-doc-empl/index.aspx</para>
    <para>Miller, G. A. (2003). The cognitive revolution: A historical perspective. <emphasis effect="italics">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</emphasis>,<emphasis effect="italics"> 7</emphasis>, 141 144.</para>
    <para>Munakata, Y., McClelland, J. L., Johnson, M. H.,   Siegler, R. S. (1997). Rethinking infant knowledge: Toward an adaptive process account of successes and failures in object permanence tasks. <emphasis effect="italics">Psychological Review</emphasis>,<emphasis effect="italics"> 104</emphasis>, 689 713.</para>
    <para>Mundasad, S. (2013). <emphasis effect="italics">Word-taste synaesthesia: Tasting names, places, and Anne Boleyn</emphasis>. Retrieved from http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-21060207</para>
    <para>Munsey, C. (2009). More states forgo a postdoc requirement. <emphasis effect="italics">Monitor on Psychology</emphasis>,<emphasis effect="italics"> 40</emphasis>, 10.</para>
    <para>National Association of School Psychologists. (n.d.). <emphasis effect="italics">Becoming a nationally certified school psychologist (NCSP). </emphasis>Retrieved from http://www.nasponline.org/CERTIFICATION/becomeNCSP.aspx</para>
    <para>Nicolas, S.,   Ferrand, L. (1999). Wundt s laboratory at Leipzig in 1891. <emphasis effect="italics">History of Psychology</emphasis>, <emphasis effect="italics">2</emphasis>, 194 203.</para>
    <para>Norcross, J. C. (n.d.) Clinical versus counseling psychology: What s the diff? Available at http://www.csun.edu/~hcpsy002/Clinical%20Versus%20Counseling%20Psychology.pdf</para>
    <para>Norcross, J. C.,   Castle, P. H. (2002). Appreciating the PsyD: The facts. <emphasis effect="italics">Eye on Psi Chi</emphasis>,<emphasis effect="italics"> 7</emphasis>, 22 26.</para>
    <para>O Connor, J. J.,   Robertson, E. F. (2002). <emphasis effect="italics">John Forbes Nash. </emphasis>Retrieved from http://www-groups.dcs.st-and.ac.uk/~history/Biographies/Nash.html</para>
    <para>O Hara, M. (n.d.). Historic review of humanistic psychology. Retrieved from http://www.ahpweb.org/index.php?option=com_k2 view=item layout=item id=14 Itemid=24</para>
    <para>Person, E. S. (1980). Sexuality as the mainstay of identity: Psychoanalytic perspectives. <emphasis effect="italics">Signs</emphasis>,<emphasis effect="italics"> 5</emphasis>, 605 630.</para>
    <para>Rantanen, J., Metspelto, R. L., Feldt, T., Pulkkinen, L.,   Kokko, K. (2007). Long-term stability in the Big Five personality traits in adulthood. <emphasis effect="italics">Scandinavian Journal of Psychology</emphasis>,<emphasis effect="italics"> 48</emphasis>, 511 518.</para>
    <para>Riggio, R. E. (2013). What is industrial/organizational psychology? <emphasis effect="italics">Psychology Today. </emphasis>Retrieved from http://www.psychologytoday.com/blog/cutting-edge-leadership/201303/what-is-industrialorganizational-psychology</para>
    <para>Sacks, O. (2007). A neurologists notebook: The abyss, music and amnesia. <emphasis effect="italics">The New Yorker. </emphasis>Retrieved from http://www.newyorker.com/reporting/2007/09/24/070924fa_fact_sacks?currentPage=all</para>
    <para>Shedler, J. (2010). The efficacy of psychodynamic psychotherapy. <emphasis effect="italics">American Psychologist</emphasis>, <emphasis effect="italics">65</emphasis>(2), 98 109.</para>
    <para>Soldz, S.,   Vaillant, G. E. (1999). The Big Five personality traits and the life course: A 45-year longitudinal study. <emphasis effect="italics">Journal of Research in Personality</emphasis>,<emphasis effect="italics"> 33</emphasis>, 208 232.</para>
    <para>Thorne, B. M.,   Henley, T. B. (2005). <emphasis effect="italics">Connections in the history and systems of psychology </emphasis>(3rd ed.). Boston, MA: Houghton Mifflin Company.</para>
    <para>Tolman, E. C. (1938). The determiners of behavior at a choice point. <emphasis effect="italics">Psychological Review</emphasis>, <emphasis effect="italics">45</emphasis>, 1 41.</para>
    <para>U.S. Department of Education, National Center for Education Statistics. (2013). <emphasis effect="italics">Digest of Education Statistics, 2012</emphasis> (NCES 2014-015).</para>
    <para>Weisstein, N. (1993). Psychology constructs the female: Or, the fantasy life of the male psychologist (with some attention to the fantasies of his friends, the male biologist and the male anthropologist). <emphasis effect="italics">Feminism and Psychology</emphasis>, <emphasis effect="italics">3</emphasis>, 195 210.</para>
    <para>Westen, D. (1998). The scientific legacy of Sigmund Freud, toward a psychodynamically informed psychological science. <emphasis effect="italics">Psychological Bulletin</emphasis>, <emphasis effect="italics">124</emphasis>, 333 371.</para>
  </section>
  <!-- END:Page -->
  <!-- END:Chapter -->
</hack-root>
