<hack-root xmlns="http://cnx.rice.edu/cnxml">
  <!-- START:Chapter -->
  <!-- START:Page -->
  <!-- Markup starts here -->
  <note class="psychology everyday-connection">
    <label>Everyday Connection</label>
    <title>Classical Conditioning at Stingray City</title>
    <para>Kate and her husband Scott recently vacationed in the Cayman Islands, and booked a boat tour to Stingray City, where they could feed and swim with the southern stingrays. The boat captain explained how the normally solitary stingrays have become accustomed to interacting with humans. About 40 years ago, fishermen began to clean fish and conch (unconditioned stimulus) at a particular sandbar near a barrier reef, and large numbers of stingrays would swim in to eat (unconditioned response) what the fishermen threw into the water; this continued for years. By the late 1980s, word of the large group of stingrays spread among scuba divers, who then started feeding them by hand. Over time, the southern stingrays in the area were classically conditioned much like Pavlov's dogs. When they hear the sound of a boat engine (neutral stimulus that becomes a conditioned stimulus), they know that they will get to eat (conditioned response).</para>
    <para>As soon as Kate and Scott reached Stingray City, over two dozen stingrays surrounded their tour boat. The couple slipped into the water with bags of squid, the stingrays favorite treat. The swarm of stingrays bumped and rubbed up against their legs like hungry cats (<link target-id="Figure06_02_Stingray"/>). Kate and Scott were able to feed, pet, and even kiss (for luck) these amazing creatures. Then all the squid was gone, and so were the stingrays.</para>
    <figure>
      <media alt="A photograph shows a woman standing in the ocean holding a stingray.">
        <image mime-type="image/jpeg" src="CNX_Psych_06_02_Stingray.jpg"/>
      </media>
      <caption>Kate holds a southern stingray at Stingray City in the Cayman Islands. These stingrays have been classically conditioned to associate the sound of a boat motor with food provided by tourists. (credit: Kathryn Dumper)</caption>
    </figure>
  </note>
  <!-- END:Page -->
  <!-- END:Chapter -->
</hack-root>
