<hack-root xmlns="http://cnx.rice.edu/cnxml">
  <!-- START:Chapter -->
  <!-- START:Page -->
  <!-- Markup starts here -->
  <note class="psychology dig-deeper">
    <label>Dig Deeper</label>
    <title>The Vaccine-Autism Myth and Retraction of Published Studies</title>
    <para>Some scientists have claimed that routine childhood vaccines cause some children to develop autism, and, in fact, several peer-reviewed publications published research making these claims. Since the initial reports, large-scale epidemiological research has suggested that vaccinations are not responsible for causing autism and that it is much safer to have your child vaccinated than not. Furthermore, several of the original studies making this claim have since been retracted.</para>
    <para>A published piece of work can be rescinded when data is called into question because of falsification, fabrication, or serious research design problems. Once rescinded, the scientific community is informed that there are serious problems with the original publication. Retractions can be initiated by the researcher who led the study, by research collaborators, by the institution that employed the researcher, or by the editorial board of the journal in which the article was originally published. In the vaccine-autism case, the retraction was made because of a significant conflict of interest in which the leading researcher had a financial interest in establishing a link between childhood vaccines and autism (Offit, 2008). Unfortunately, the initial studies received so much media attention that many parents around the world became hesitant to have their children vaccinated (<link target-id="CNX_Psych_02_05_vaccine"/>). For more information about how the vaccine/autism story unfolded, as well as the repercussions of this story, take a look at Paul Offit's book, <emphasis effect="italics">Autism's False Prophets: Bad Science, Risky Medicine, and the Search for a Cure.</emphasis></para>
  </note>
  <!-- END:Page -->
  <!-- END:Chapter -->
</hack-root>
