<hack-root xmlns="http://cnx.rice.edu/cnxml">
  <!-- START:Chapter -->
  <!-- START:Page -->
  <!-- Markup starts here -->
  <note class="psychology what-do-you-think">
    <label>What Do You Think?</label>
    <title>The Meaning of Language</title>
    <para>Think about what you know of other languages; perhaps you even speak multiple languages. Imagine for a moment that your closest friend fluently speaks more than one language. Do you think that friend thinks differently, depending on which language is being spoken? You may know a few words that are not translatable from their original language into English. For example, the Portuguese word <emphasis effect="italics">saudade </emphasis>originated during the 15th century, when Portuguese sailors left home to explore the seas and travel to Africa or Asia. Those left behind described the emptiness and fondness they felt as <emphasis effect="italics">saudade </emphasis>(<link target-id="Figure_07_02_Saudade"/>)<emphasis effect="italics">.</emphasis> The word came to express many meanings, including loss, nostalgia, yearning, warm memories, and hope. There is no single word in English that includes all of those emotions in a single description. Do words such as <emphasis effect="italics">saudade</emphasis> indicate that different languages produce different patterns of thought in people? What do you think??</para>
    <figure>
      <media alt="Photograph A shows a painting of a person leaning against a ledge, slumped sideways over a box. Photograph B shows a painting of a person reading by a window.">
        <image mime-type="image/jpeg" src="CNX_Psych_07_02_Saudade.jpg"/>
      </media>
      <caption>These two works of art depict <emphasis effect="italics">saudade</emphasis>. (a) <emphasis effect="italics">Saudade de N'poles</emphasis>, which is translated into missing Naples, was painted by Bertha Worms in 1895. (b) Almeida J'nior painted <emphasis effect="italics">Saudade </emphasis>in 1899.</caption>
    </figure>
  </note>
  <!-- END:Page -->
  <!-- END:Chapter -->
</hack-root>
