<hack-root xmlns="http://cnx.rice.edu/cnxml">
  <!-- START:Chapter -->
  <!-- START:Page -->
  <!-- Markup starts here -->
  <section id="fs-idp75215696" class="exercises">
    <title>Chemistry End of Chapter Exercises</title>
    <exercise id="fs-idm34987968">
      <problem id="fs-idm4947040">
        <para id="fs-idm59206592">Explain how you could experimentally determine whether the outside temperature is higher or lower than 0 &#xB0;C (32 &#xB0;F) without using a thermometer.</para>
      </problem>
      <solution id="fs-idp19762080">
        <para id="fs-idm40521792">Place a glass of water outside. It will freeze if the temperature is below 0 &#xB0;C.</para>
      </solution>
    </exercise>
    <exercise id="fs-idp45595424">
      <problem id="fs-idp64708304">
        <para id="fs-idp42446672">Identify each of the following statements as being most similar to a hypothesis, a law, or a theory. Explain your reasoning.</para>
        <para id="fs-idp109329824">(a) Falling barometric pressure precedes the onset of bad weather.</para>
        <para id="fs-idp71047280">(b) All life on earth has evolved from a common, primitive organism through the process of natural selection.</para>
        <para id="fs-idp109280880">(c) My truck&#x2019;s gas mileage has dropped significantly, probably because it&#x2019;s due for a tune-up.</para>
      </problem>
    </exercise>
    <exercise id="fs-idp38309200">
      <problem id="fs-idp83503984">
        <para id="fs-idp4603232">Identify each of the following statements as being most similar to a hypothesis, a law, or a theory. Explain your reasoning.</para>
        <para id="fs-idp30515744">(a) The pressure of a sample of gas is directly proportional to the temperature of the gas.</para>
        <para id="fs-idp71063392">(b) Matter consists of tiny particles that can combine in specific ratios to form substances with specific properties.</para>
        <para id="fs-idp23193248">(c) At a higher temperature, solids (such as salt or sugar) will dissolve better in water.</para>
      </problem>
      <solution id="fs-idp5011648">
        <para id="fs-idm53320912">(a) law (states a consistently observed phenomenon, can be used for prediction); (b) theory (a widely accepted explanation of the behavior of matter); (c) hypothesis (a tentative explanation, can be investigated by experimentation)</para>
      </solution>
    </exercise>
    <exercise id="fs-idm58468592">
      <problem id="fs-idm2661072">
        <para id="fs-idm59152592">Identify each of the underlined items as a part of either the macroscopic domain, the microscopic domain, or the symbolic domain of chemistry. For any in the symbolic domain, indicate whether they are symbols for a macroscopic or a microscopic feature.</para>
        <para id="fs-idp94102864">(a) The mass of a <emphasis effect="underline">lead pipe</emphasis> is 14 lb.</para>
        <para id="fs-idp77253536">(b) The mass of a certain <emphasis effect="underline">chlorine atom</emphasis> is 35 amu.</para>
        <para id="fs-idp71129152">(c) A bottle with a label that reads <emphasis effect="underline">Al</emphasis> contains aluminum metal.</para>
        <para id="fs-idp71050048">(d) <emphasis effect="underline">Al</emphasis> is the symbol for an aluminum atom.</para>
      </problem>
    </exercise>
    <exercise id="fs-idm67489232">
      <problem id="fs-idp67411776">
        <para id="fs-idp54908512">Identify each of the underlined items as a part of either the macroscopic domain, the microscopic domain, or the symbolic domain of chemistry. For those in the symbolic domain, indicate whether they are symbols for a macroscopic or a microscopic feature.</para>
        <para id="fs-idp19466944">(a) A certain molecule contains one <emphasis effect="underline">H</emphasis> atom and one Cl atom.</para>
        <para id="fs-idp55370768">(b) <emphasis effect="underline">Copper wire</emphasis> has a density of about 8 g/cm<sup>3</sup>.</para>
        <para id="fs-idp68623088">(c) The bottle contains 15 grams of <emphasis effect="underline">Ni powder</emphasis>.</para>
        <para id="fs-idp23452688">(d) A <emphasis effect="underline">sulfur molecule</emphasis> is composed of eight sulfur atoms.</para>
      </problem>
      <solution id="fs-idp31026272">
        <para id="fs-idm56463840">(a) symbolic, microscopic; (b) macroscopic; (c) symbolic, macroscopic; (d) microscopic</para>
      </solution>
    </exercise>
    <exercise id="fs-idp6505632">
      <problem id="fs-idm59649392">
        <para id="fs-idp112708912">According to one theory, the pressure of a gas increases as its volume decreases because the molecules in the gas have to move a shorter distance to hit the walls of the container. Does this theory follow a macroscopic or microscopic description of chemical behavior? Explain your answer.</para>
      </problem>
    </exercise>
    <exercise id="fs-idp40361152">
      <problem id="fs-idp111357888">
        <para id="fs-idp72952208">The amount of heat required to melt 2 lbs of ice is twice the amount of heat required to melt 1 lb of ice. Is this observation a macroscopic or microscopic description of chemical behavior? Explain your answer.</para>
      </problem>
      <solution id="fs-idm17181616">
        <para id="fs-idm78140032">Macroscopic. The heat required is determined from macroscopic properties.</para>
      </solution>
    </exercise>
  </section>
  <!-- END:Page -->
  <!-- END:Chapter -->
</hack-root>
