<hack-root xmlns="http://cnx.rice.edu/cnxml">
  <!-- START:Chapter -->
  <!-- START:Page -->
  <!-- Markup starts here -->
  <note class="sciences-interconnect">
    <title>Counting Neurotransmitter Molecules in the Brain</title>
    <para id="fs-idm4217280">The brain is the control center of the central nervous system (<a class="autogenerated-content" href="#CNX_Chem_03_01_brain">Figure 3.9</a>). It sends and receives signals to and from muscles and other internal organs to monitor and control their functions; it processes stimuli detected by sensory organs to guide interactions with the external world; and it houses the complex physiological processes that give rise to our intellect and emotions. The broad field of neuroscience spans all aspects of the structure and function of the central nervous system, including research on the anatomy and physiology of the brain. Great progress has been made in brain research over the past few decades, and the BRAIN Initiative, a federal initiative announced in 2013, aims to accelerate and capitalize on these advances through the concerted efforts of various industrial, academic, and government agencies (more details available at www.whitehouse.gov/share/brain-initiative).</para>
    <div class="os-figure">
      <figure id="CNX_Chem_03_01_brain">
        <span data-alt="Two pictures are shown. The left picture shows the human brain. The right picture is a microscopic image that depicts two large irregularly shaped masses in a field of threadlike material interspersed with smaller, relatively round masses. The two larger masses are labeled with arrows and the phrase “Neuron cells.”" data-type="media" id="fs-idp71769904"><img alt="Two pictures are shown. The left picture shows the human brain. The right picture is a microscopic image that depicts two large irregularly shaped masses in a field of threadlike material interspersed with smaller, relatively round masses. The two larger masses are labeled with arrows and the phrase “Neuron cells.”" data-media-type="image/jpeg" id="39221" src="/resources/76d8dfe54c228341589ebb97bc57dcd64142b234"></span>
      </figure>
      <div class="os-caption-container">
        <span class="os-title-label">Figure </span><span class="os-number">3.9</span><span class="os-divider"> </span><span class="os-divider"> </span><span class="os-caption">(a) A typical human brain weighs about 1.5 kg and occupies a volume of roughly 1.1 L. (b) Information is transmitted in brain tissue and throughout the central nervous system by specialized cells called neurons (micrograph shows cells at 1600× magnification).</span>
      </div>
    </div>
  </note>
  <!-- END:Page -->
  <!-- END:Chapter -->
</hack-root>
