<hack-root xmlns="http://cnx.rice.edu/cnxml">
  <!-- START:Chapter -->
  <!-- START:Page -->
  <!-- Markup starts here -->
  <note id="fs-idm210419280" class="spotlight-ethics">
    <title>Sample Feature Box Using Graphic Design Client Feedback
  </title>
    <para id="fs-idm183896704">This is the Description of the &#x201C;Spotlight on Ethics&#x201D; FB from the WEG: This feature will highlight an ethics issue related to the concept, skill, or activity being taught in the text. These might discuss in relation to a real-world case, might dig deeper into an ethical concept being discussed, or might present an ethical dilemma for the student to think through. There will be 1&#x2013;2 Spotlight on Ethics boxes in each chapter.
  </para>
    <para id="fs-idm210426912">I was wondering if my cat could be placed over the logo in the flyer i know you've made thirty iterations but can we go back to the first one that was the best version, yet can you punch up the fun level on these icons for I want you to take it to the next level, and make the font bigger. Needs to be sleeker try making it a bit less blah the target audience is males and females aged zero and up, I like it, but can the snow look a little warmer. Concept is bang on, but can we look at a better execution that&#x2019;s not what i saw in my head at all anyway, you are the designer, you know what to do. Can you make the font bigger? i think this should be fairly easy so if you just want to have a look I know somebody who can do this for a reasonable cost. </para>
    <para id="fs-idm174409360">Need more geometry patterns can we go back to the first one that was the best version so will royalties in the company do instead of cash other agencies charge much less, so is this the best we can do I think we need to start from scratch, and we don't need a backup, it never goes down!. That sandwich needs to be more playful. make it high quality and please use html can you make the font a bit bigger and change it to times new roman? jazz it up a little bit make the picture of the cupcake look delicious</para>
    <quote id="fs-idm215874176">Make the purple more well, purple-er it looks so empty add some more hearts can you add a bit of pastel pink and baby blue because the purple alone looks too fancy okay can you put a cute quote on the right side of the site? oh no it looks messed up! i think we need to start from scratch. I know somebody who can do this for a reasonable cost i was wondering if my cat could be placed over the logo in the flyer, can you make it pop, for make it sexy, yet can you please change the color theme of the website to pink and purple? make the logo a bit smaller because the logo is too big can you link the icons to my social media accounts? oh and please put pictures of cats everywhere i was wondering if my cat could be placed over the logo in the flyer.</quote>
    <para id="fs-idm222813520">Try making it a bit less blah it's great, can you add a beard though We try your eye, but can you change everything? i love it, but can you invert all colors? oh and please put pictures of cats everywhere, for I really like the color but can you change it Start on it today and we will talk about what i want next time We are a startup. Make the font bigger can you make it look like this clipart i found.
  </para>
  </note>
  <!-- END:Page -->
  <!-- END:Chapter -->
</hack-root>
