<hack-root xmlns="http://cnx.rice.edu/cnxml">
  <!-- START:Chapter -->
  <!-- START:Page -->
  <!-- Markup starts here -->
  <div class="work-it-out" data-type="note" id="auto_2d9dac56-8a42-4fd2-96db-a5bfe3a8ffc2_eip-id1171825322836"><div data-type="title" id="auto_2d9dac56-8a42-4fd2-96db-a5bfe3a8ffc2_41937">Transactions at Debbie’s Dairy Farm</div><p id="auto_2d9dac56-8a42-4fd2-96db-a5bfe3a8ffc2_eip-id1171825260744">Debbie’s Dairy Farm had the following transactions.

  </p><ol id="eip-756" type="A"><li>Debbie ordered shelving worth $750.</li>
  <li>Debbie’s selling price on a gallon of milk is $3.00. She finds out that most local stores are charging $3.50. Based on this information, she decides to increase her price to $3.25. She has an employee put a new price sticker on each gallon.</li>
  <li>A customer buys a gallon of milk paying cash.</li>
  <li>The shelving is delivered with an invoice for $750.</li>
  </ol><p id="auto_2d9dac56-8a42-4fd2-96db-a5bfe3a8ffc2_eip-138">Which events will be recorded in the accounting system?

  </p><ol id="eip-id1171812680131" type="A">
  <li>Debbie did not yet receive the shelving, it has only been ordered, so there is no asset yet. She also does not have a liability yet because she has not received the asset yet. Therefore, Debbie will not record the transaction.</li>
  <li>Changing prices does not have an impact on the company at the time the price is changed. All that happened was that a new price sticker was placed on the milk. Debbie still has all of the milk and has not received any money. </li>
  <li>Debbie now has a transaction to record. She has received cash and the customer has taken some of her inventory of milk. We have an increase in one asset (cash) and a decrease in another asset (inventory.)</li>
  <li>The asset has been delivered so Debbie has a new asset and must record the increase. She also has an increase in her liabilities as she accepted delivery of the shelving but has not paid for it.</li>

  </ol></div>
  <!-- END:Page -->
  <!-- END:Chapter -->
</hack-root>
