<hack-root xmlns="http://cnx.rice.edu/cnxml">
  <!-- START:Chapter -->
  <!-- START:Page -->
  <!-- Markup starts here -->
  <div class="middle-ground" data-type="note">
    <div data-type="title">Debating the Need for a Bill of Rights</div>
    <p>One of the most serious debates between the Federalists and the Anti-Federalists was over the necessity of limiting the power of the new federal government with a Bill of Rights. As we saw in this section, the Federalists believed a Bill of Rights was unnecessary&#x2014;and perhaps even dangerous to liberty, because it might invite violations of rights that weren&#x2019;t included in it&#x2014;while the Anti-Federalists thought the national government would prove adept at expanding its powers and influence and that citizens couldn&#x2019;t depend on the good judgment of Congress alone to protect their rights.</p>
    <p>As George Washington&#x2019;s call for a bill of rights in his first inaugural address suggested, while the Federalists ultimately had to add the Bill of Rights to the Constitution in order to win ratification, and the Anti-Federalists would soon be proved right that the national government might intrude on civil liberties. In 1798, at the behest of President John Adams during the Quasi-War with France, Congress passed a series of four laws collectively known as the Alien and Sedition Acts. These were drafted to allow the president to imprison or deport foreign citizens he believed were &#x201C;dangerous to the peace and safety of the United States&#x201D; and to restrict speech and newspaper articles that were critical of the federal government or its officials; the laws were primarily used against members and supporters of the opposition Democratic-Republican Party.</p>
    <p>State laws and constitutions protecting free speech and freedom of the press proved ineffective in limiting this new federal power. Although the courts did not decide on the constitutionality of these laws at the time, most scholars believe the Sedition Act, in particular, would be unconstitutional if it had remained in effect. Three of the four laws were repealed in the Jefferson administration, but one&#x2014;the Alien Enemies Act&#x2014;remains on the books today. Two centuries later, the issue of free speech and freedom of the press during times of international conflict remains a subject of public debate.</p>
    <p>
      <em data-effect="italics">Should the government be able to restrict or censor unpatriotic, disloyal, or critical speech in times of international conflict? How much freedom should journalists have to report on stories from the perspective of enemies or to repeat propaganda from opposing forces?</em>
    </p>
  </div>
  <!-- END:Page -->
  <!-- END:Chapter -->
</hack-root>
