<hack-root xmlns="http://cnx.rice.edu/cnxml">
  <!-- START:Chapter -->
  <!-- START:Page -->
  <!-- Markup starts here -->
  <note class="get-connected"><title>Where to Register?</title><para>Across the United States, over twenty million college and university students begin classes each fall, many away from home. The simple act of moving away to college presents a <term class="no-emphasis">voter registration</term> problem. Elections are local. Each citizen lives in a district with state legislators, city council or other local elected representatives, a U.S. House of Representatives member, and more. State and national laws require voters to reside in their districts, but students are an unusual case. They often hold temporary residency while at school and return home for the summer. Therefore, they have to decide whether to register to vote near campus or vote back in their home district. What are the pros and cons of each option?</para><para>Maintaining voter registration back home is legal in most states, assuming a student holds only temporary residency at school. This may be the best plan, because students are likely more familiar with local politicians and issues. But it requires the student to either go home to vote or apply for an absentee ballot. With classes, clubs, work, and more, it may be difficult to remember this task. One study found that students living more than two hours from home were less likely to vote than students living within thirty minutes of campus, which is not surprising.<cite target-id="rf-27"><note class="reference" display="inline" id="rf-27">Richard Niemi and Michael Hanmer. 2010. &#x201C;Voter Turnout Among College Students: New Data and a Rethinking of Traditional Theories,&#x201D; <emphasis effect="italics">Social Science Quarterly</emphasis> 91, No. 2: 301&#x2013;323.</note></cite></para><para>Registering to vote near campus makes it easier to vote, but it requires an extra step that students may forget (<link target-id="OSC_AmGov_07_01_CampusVote"/>). And in many states, registration to vote in a November election takes place in October, just when students are acclimating to the semester. They must also become familiar with local candidates and issues, which takes time and effort they may not have. But they will not have to travel to vote, and their vote is more likely to affect their college and local town.</para>\
    <para><emphasis effect="italics">Have you registered to vote in your college area, or will you vote back home? What factors influenced your decision about where to vote?</emphasis></para></note>
  <!-- END:Page -->
  <!-- END:Chapter -->
</hack-root>
