<hack-root xmlns="http://cnx.rice.edu/cnxml">
  <!-- START:Chapter -->
  <!-- START:Page -->
  <!-- Markup starts here -->
  <div class="get-connected" data-type="note">
    <div data-type="title">Getting Involved</div>
    <p>In many ways, the pluralists were right. There is plenty of room for average citizens to become active in government, whether it is through a city council subcommittee or another type of local organization. Civic organizations always need volunteers, sometimes for only a short while and sometimes for much longer.</p>
    <p>For example, <a href="https://openstax.org/l/29comcause">Common Cause</a> is a non-partisan organization that seeks to hold government accountable for its actions. It calls for campaign finance reform and paper verification of votes registered on electronic voting machines. Voters would then receive proof that the machine recorded their actual vote. This would help to detect faulty machines that were inaccurately tabulating votes or election fraud. Therefore, one could be sure that election results were reliable and that the winning candidate had in fact received the votes counted in their favor. <span class="no-emphasis" data-type="term">Common Cause</span> has also advocated that the Electoral College be done away with and that presidential elections be decided solely on the basis of the popular vote.</p>
    <p>Follow-up activity: Choose one of the following websites to connect with organizations and interest groups in need of help:</p>
    <ul data-bullet-style="bullet">
      <li><a href="https://openstax.org/l/29comcause">Common Cause</a>;</li>
      <li><a href="https://openstax.org/l/29takeactcen">Friends of the Earth</a> which mobilizes people to protect the natural environment;</li>
      <li><a href="https://openstax.org/l/29grassrootsint">Grassroots International</a> which works for global justice;</li>
      <li><a href="https://openstax.org/l/29famrescouncil">The Family Research Council</a> which promotes traditional marriage and Judeo-Christian values; or</li>
      <li><a href="https://openstax.org/l/29eagleforum">Eagle Forum</a> which supports greater restrictions on immigration and fewer restrictions on home schooling.</li>
    </ul>
  </div>
  <!-- END:Page -->
  <!-- END:Chapter -->
</hack-root>
