<hack-root xmlns="http://cnx.rice.edu/cnxml">
  <!-- START:Chapter -->
  <!-- START:Page -->
  <!-- Markup starts here -->
  <section id="fs-idm249219424" class="references">
    <title>Bibliography</title>
    <para id="fs-idm252264320">Adams, William Y. 1983. Once More to the Fray: Further Reflections on Navajo Kinship and Residence. <emphasis effect="italics">Journal of Anthropological Research</emphasis> 39(4):393-414. Adoption Network accessed at: https://adoptionnetwork.com/adoption-statistics#:~:text=There%20are%20about%201.5%20million,one%20out%20of%2050%20children.
  </para>
    <para id="fs-idm242166976">Bao, Jiemin. 2008. Denaturalizing Polygyny in Bangkok, Thailand. <emphasis effect="italics">Ethnology</emphasis> 47(2/3):145-61.</para>
    <para id="fs-idm242768304">Bao, Jiemin. 2008. Denaturalizing Polygyny in Bangkok, Thailand. Ethnology 47(2/3):145-61.</para>
    <para id="fs-idm238620128">Bao, Jiemin. 2003. The Gendered Biopolitics of Marriage and Immigration: A Study of pre-1949 Chinese Immigrants in Thailand. <emphasis effect="italics">Journal of Southeast Asian Studies</emphasis> 34(1);127-51.</para>
    <para id="fs-idm249726992">Child Welfare League of America: WLA (2019) accessed at: https://www.cwla.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/National-2019.pdf</para>
    <para id="fs-idm255221616">Ember, Carol R., Melvin Ember, and Peter Peregrine. 2002. <emphasis effect="italics">Anthropology</emphasis>. 10th ed. Prentice Hall. [UPDATE PUB YEAR]</para>
    <para id="fs-idm251387952">Foster, George. 1953. Cofrad&#xED;a and Compadrazgo in Spain and Spanish America. <emphasis effect="italics">Southwestern Journal of Anthropology</emphasis> Vol 9:1-28.</para>
    <para id="fs-idm245267408">Foster, George. 1961. The Dyadic Contract in Tzintzuntzan: A Patron-Client Relationship. <emphasis effect="italics">American Anthropologist</emphasis> 65: 1280-94.</para>
    <para id="fs-idm244404752">Fox, Robin. 1977. <emphasis effect="italics">Kinship and Marriage: An Anthropological Perspective</emphasis>. Penguin.</para>
    <para id="fs-idm254576816">Goldstein, Melvyn C. 1987. When Brothers Share a Wife. <emphasis effect="italics">Natural History</emphasis> 96(3):38-49.</para>
    <para id="fs-idm241803792">Haile, Berard. 1942. Why the Navajo Hogan? <emphasis effect="italics">Primitive Man</emphasis> 15(3-4): 39-56.</para>
    <para id="fs-idm249930432">Hua, Cai. 2008. <emphasis effect="italics">A Society without Fathers or Husbands: The Na of China</emphasis>. Zone Bks. Translated by Asti Hustvedt.</para>
    <para id="fs-idm243751824">Ingar, Carmen Mez. 2015. Necesidad de desarrollar el derecho consuetudinario. <emphasis effect="italics">Revista Jur&#xED;dica &#x201C;Docentia et Investigatio&#x201D;</emphasis> 17(1):21-30.</para>
    <para id="fs-idm246539776">Jacobi, Jeffrey S. 2006. Two Spirits, Two Eras, Same Sex: For a Traditionalist Perspective on Native American Tribal Same-Sex Marriage Policy. <emphasis effect="italics">University of Michigan Journal of Law Reform</emphasis> 39(4):823-50.</para>
    <para id="fs-idm253985296">Keesing, Felix. 1958. <emphasis effect="italics">Cultural Anthropology</emphasis>. Holt, Rinehart and Winston, Inc.</para>
    <para id="fs-idm249982208">Lamphere, Louise. 2005. Replacing Heteronormative Views of Kinship and Marriage. American Ethnologist 32(1):34-36.</para>
    <para id="fs-idm238113728">Leinaweaver, Jessaca. 2014. Informal Kinship-Based Fostering Around the World: Anthropological Findings. <emphasis effect="italics">Child Development Perspectives</emphasis> 8(3):131-135.</para>
    <para id="fs-idm409778288">Malinowski, Bronislaw. 1922. <emphasis effect="italics">Argonauts of the Western Pacific</emphasis>. Routledge and Kegan Paul Ltd.</para>
    <para id="fs-idm405249376">Malinowski, Bronislaw. 1930. Kinship. <emphasis effect="italics">Man</emphasis>, Vol. 30, pp. 19-20.</para>
    <para id="fs-idm416699392">Mintz, Sidney W. and Eric R. Wolf. 1950. An Analysis of Ritual Co-Parenthood (Compadrazgo). <emphasis effect="italics">Southwestern Journal of Anthropology</emphasis> 6(4):341-68.</para>
    <para id="fs-idm412452608">Morgan, Lewis Henry. 1871. <emphasis effect="italics">Systems of Consanguinity and Affinity of the Human Family.</emphasis> Smithsonian Institution. </para>
    <para id="fs-idm250430992">Murphy, Yolanda and Robert Murphy. 1985. <emphasis effect="italics">Women of the Forest</emphasis>. 2nd ed. Columbia Univ Press.</para>
    <para id="fs-idm247102896">Peng, Jessica. 2018. To Marry or Not to Marry? Consensual Union is Popular in Iceland. Accessed at: https://grapevine.is/mag/articles/2018/06/04/to-marry-or-not-to-marry-consensual-union-is-popular-in-iceland/.</para>
    <para id="fs-idm230510384">Pew Research (2019) accessed at: https://www.pewresearch.org/fact-tank/2019/12/12/u-s-children-more-likely-than-children-in-other-countries-to-live-with-just-one-parent/</para>
    <para id="fs-idm243310448">Radcliffe-Brown, A.R. 1922. <emphasis effect="italics">The Andaman Islanders</emphasis>. Cambridge Univ Press.</para>
    <para id="fs-idm232462416">Radcliffe-Brown, A.R. 1952. <emphasis effect="italics">Structure and Function in Primitive Society</emphasis>. Cohen and West Ltd.</para>
    <para id="fs-idm236638112">Rivers, W.H.R. 1910. The Genealogical Method of Anthropological Inquiry. <emphasis effect="italics">The Sociological Review</emphasis> 3(1):1-12.</para>
    <para id="fs-idm230252992">Schulte, Ernest L. 1965. <emphasis effect="italics">Manual for Kinship Analysis</emphasis>. Studies in Anthropological Method. Holt, Rinehart and Winston, Inc.</para>
    <para id="fs-idm241765328">Shapiro, Warren. 2015. Not &#x201C;From the Natives&#x2019; Point of View&#x201D;: Why the New Kinship Studies Need the Old Kinship Terminologies. <emphasis effect="italics">Anthropos</emphasis> 110(1):1-13.</para>
    <para id="fs-idm242647920">Sitlhou, Hoineilhing. 2018. Symbolism of Bride Wealth and Gift-giving in Marriage System of the Kukis. Indian Anthropologist 48(1):31-46.</para>
    <para id="fs-idm243149488">Stone, Linda. 1998. <emphasis effect="italics">Kinship and Gender: An Introduction</emphasis>. Westview Press.</para>
    <para id="fs-idm253191744">Schwartze, Lucas J. 2010. Grave Vows: A Cross-Cultural Examination of the Varying Forms of Ghost Marriage among Five Societies. Nebraska Anthropologist 60:82-95.</para>
    <para id="fs-idm244841360">Topley, Marjorie. 1955. Ghost Marriage among the Singapore Chinese. <emphasis effect="italics">Man</emphasis> 55:29-30.</para>
    <para id="fs-idm247822064">US Census (2016) accessed at: https://www.census.gov/newsroom/press-releases/2016/cb16-192.html.</para>
    <para id="fs-idm236011232">Van Vleet, Krista E. 2008. <emphasis effect="italics">Performing Kinship: Narrative, Gender, and the Intimacies of Power in the Andes</emphasis>. Austin: Univ of Texas.</para>
    <para id="fs-idm250740688">Zeitzen, Miriam Koktvedgaard. 2008. <emphasis effect="italics">Polygamy: A Cross-Cultural Analysis</emphasis>. Berg.</para>
  </section>
  <!-- END:Page -->
  <!-- END:Chapter -->
</hack-root>
