<hack-root xmlns="http://cnx.rice.edu/cnxml">
  <!-- START:Chapter -->
  <!-- START:Page -->
  <!-- Markup starts here -->
  <section class="references">
    <title>References</title>
    <para/>
    <para>American Cancer Society. (n.d.). History of the cancer prevention studies<emphasis effect="italics">.</emphasis> Retrieved from http://www.cancer.org/research/researchtopreventcancer/history-cancer-prevention-study</para>
    <para/>
    <para/>
    <para>Arnett, J. (2008). The neglected 95%: Why American psychology needs to become less American. <emphasis effect="italics">American Psychologist, 63</emphasis>(7)<emphasis effect="italics">,</emphasis> 602&#x2013;614.</para>
    <para>Aschwanden, Ch. (2018). Psychology&#x2019;s Replication Crisis Has Made The Field Better. https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/psychologys-replication-crisis-has-made-the-field-better/</para>
    <para>Barnett, W. S. (2011). Effectiveness of Early Educational Intervention. Science, 333, 975-978.</para>
    <para>Barton, B. A., Eldridge, A. L., Thompson, D., Affenito, S. G., Striegel-Moore, R. H., Franko, D. L., . . . Crockett, S. J. (2005). The relationship of breakfast and cereal consumption to nutrient intake and body mass index: The national heart, lung, and blood institute growth and health study. <emphasis effect="italics">Journal of the American Dietetic Association, 105</emphasis>(9), 1383&#x2013;1389. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jada.2005.06.003</para>
    <para>Chwalisz, K., Diener, E., &amp; Gallagher, D. (1988). Autonomic arousal feedback and emotional experience: Evidence from the spinal cord injured. <emphasis effect="italics">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology, 54</emphasis>, 820&#x2013;828.</para>
    <para>Clayton, R. R., Cattarello, A. M., &amp; Johnstone, B. M. (1996). The effectiveness of Drug Abuse Resistance Education (Project DARE): 5-year follow-up results. <emphasis effect="italics">Preventive Medicine: An International Journal Devoted to Practice and Theory, 25</emphasis>(3), 307&#x2013;318. doi:10.1006/pmed.1996.0061</para>
    <para/>
    <para>Dominus, S. (2011, May 25). Could conjoined twins share a mind? <emphasis effect="italics">New York Times Sunday Magazine</emphasis>. Retrieved from http://www.nytimes.com/2011/05/29/magazine/could-conjoined-twins-share-a-mind.html?_r=5&amp;hp&amp;</para>
    <para>Ennett, S. T., Tobler, N. S., Ringwalt, C. L., &amp; Flewelling, R. L. (1994). How effective is drug abuse resistance education? A meta-analysis of Project DARE outcome evaluations. <emphasis effect="italics">American Journal of Public Health, 84</emphasis>(9), 1394&#x2013;1401. doi:10.2105/AJPH.84.9.1394</para>
    <para>Fanger, S. M., Frankel, L. A., &amp; Hazen, N. (2012). Peer exclusion in preschool children&#x2019;s play: Naturalistic observations in a playground setting. <emphasis effect="italics">Merrill-Palmer Quarterly</emphasis>, <emphasis effect="italics">58,</emphasis> 224&#x2013;254.</para>
    <para>Fiedler, K. (2004). Illusory correlation. In R. F. Pohl (Ed.), <emphasis effect="italics">Cognitive illusions: A handbook on fallacies and biases in thinking, judgment and memory</emphasis> (pp. 97&#x2013;114). New York, NY: Psychology Press.</para>
    <para>Frankfort-Nachmias, Ch., Nachmias, D. (2001). Metody badawcze w naukach spo&#x142;ecznych. Wydawnictwo Zysk i S - ka.</para>
    <para>Frantzen, L. B., Trevi&#xF1;o, R. P., Echon, R. M., Garcia-Dominic, O., &amp; DiMarco, N. (2013). Association between frequency of ready-to-eat cereal consumption, nutrient intakes, and body mass index in fourth- to sixth-grade low-income minority children. <emphasis effect="italics">Journal of the Academy of Nutrition and Dietetics, 113</emphasis>(4), 511&#x2013;519.</para>
    <para>Harper, J. (2013, July 5). Ice cream and crime: Where cold cuisine and hot disputes intersect. <emphasis effect="italics">The Times-Picaune.</emphasis> Retrieved from http://www.nola.com/crime/index.ssf/2013/07/ice_cream_and_crime_where_hot.html</para>
    <para>Jenkins, W. J., Ruppel, S. E., Kizer, J. B., Yehl, J. L., &amp; Griffin, J. L. (2012). An examination of post 9-11 attitudes towards Arab Americans. <emphasis effect="italics">North American Journal of Psychology, 14</emphasis>, 77&#x2013;84.</para>
    <para>Jones, J. M. (2013, May 13). Same-sex marriage support solidifies above 50% in U.S. <emphasis effect="italics">Gallup Politics.</emphasis> Retrieved from http://www.gallup.com/poll/162398/sex-marriage-support-solidifies-above.aspx</para>
    <para>Kobrin, J. L., Patterson, B. F., Shaw, E. J., Mattern, K. D., &amp; Barbuti, S. M. (2008). <emphasis effect="italics">Validity of the SAT for predicting first-year college grade point average</emphasis> (Research Report No. 2008-5). Retrieved from https://research.collegeboard.org/sites/default/files/publications/2012/7/researchreport-2008-5-validity-sat-predicting-first-year-college-grade-point-average.pdf</para>
    <para>Kosydar-Bochenek, J., Lewandowski, B., Ozga, D., Wo&#x17A;niak, K. (2016). Przegl&#x105;d narz&#x119;dzi diagnostycznych i metod pomiaru zespo&#x142;u stresu pourazowego (Posttraumatic Stress Disorder, PTSD) z mo&#x17C;liwo&#x15B;ci&#x105; wykorzystania w&#x15B;r&#xF3;d ratownik&#xF3;w medycznych. Pielegniarstwo XXI wieku, 15, 45-49.</para>
    <para>Lewin, T. (2014, March 5). A new SAT aims to realign with schoolwork. <emphasis effect="italics">New York Times</emphasis>. Retreived from http://www.nytimes.com/2014/03/06/education/major-changes-in-sat-announced-by-college-board.html.</para>
    <para>Lowcock, E. C., Cotterchio, M., Anderson, L. N., Boucher, B. A., &amp; El-Sohemy, A. (2013). High coffee intake, but not caffeine, is associated with reduced estrogen receptor negative and postmenopausal breast cancer risk with no effect modification by CYP1A2 genotype. <emphasis effect="italics">Nutrition and Cancer, 65</emphasis>(3), 398&#x2013;409. doi:10.1080/01635581.2013.768348</para>
    <para>Lowry, M., Dean, K., &amp; Manders, K. (2010). The link between sleep quantity and academic performance for the college student. <emphasis effect="italics">Sentience: The University of Minnesota Undergraduate Journal of Psychology,</emphasis> <emphasis effect="italics">3</emphasis>(Spring), 16&#x2013;19. Retrieved from http://www.psych.umn.edu/sentience/files/SENTIENCE_Vol3.pdf</para>
    <para>Lynam, D. R., Milich, R., Zimmerman, R., Novak, S. P., Logan, T. K., Martin, C., . . . Clayton, R. (1999). Project DARE: No effects at 10-year follow-up. <emphasis effect="italics">Journal of Consulting and Clinical Psychology, 67</emphasis>(4), 590&#x2013;593. doi:10.1037/0022-006X.67.4.590</para>
    <para>Massimini, M., Peterson, M. (2009). Information and Communication Technology: Affects on U.S. College Students. Cyberpsychology: Journal of Psychosocial Research on Cyberspace, 3, Article 3.</para>
    <para>McKie, R. (2010, June 26). Chimps with everything: Jane Goodall&#x2019;s 50 years in the jungle. <emphasis effect="italics">The Guardian</emphasis>. Retrieved from http://www.theguardian.com/science/2010/jun/27/jane-goodall-chimps-africa-interview</para>
    <para>Narodowe Centrum Nauki (2016). Zalecenia rady narodowego centrum nauki dotycz&#x105;ce bada&#x144; z udzia&#x142;em ludzi. https://www.ncn.gov.pl/sites/default/files/pliki/2016_zalecenia_Rady_NCN_dot_etyki_badan.pdf</para>
    <para>Neil, A. L., Christensen, H. (2009). Efficacy and Effectiveness of School-Based Prevention and Early Intervention Programs for Anxiety. Clinical Psychology Review, 29, 208- 215.</para>
    <para>Offit, P. (2008). <emphasis effect="italics">Autism's false prophets: Bad science, risky medicine, and the search for a cure</emphasis>. New York: Columbia University Press.</para>
    <para>Perkins, H. W., Haines, M. P., &amp; Rice, R. (2005). Misperceiving the college drinking norm and related problems: A nationwide study of exposure to prevention information, perceived norms and student alcohol misuse. <emphasis effect="italics">J. Stud. Alcohol, 66</emphasis>(4), 470&#x2013;478.</para>
    <para>Peters-Scheffer, N., Didden, R., Korzilius, H., Sturmey, P. (2011). A meta-analytic study on the effectiveness of comprehensive ABA-based early intervention programs for children with autism spectrum disorders. Research in Autism Spectrum Disorders, 5, 60-69.</para>
    <para/>
    <para/>
    <para>Rodgers, J. L., Shrout, P. E. (2018). Psychology&#x2019;s replication crisis as scientific opportunity: A pr&#xE9;cis for policymakers. Policy Insights from the Behavioral and Brain Sciences, 5(, 134&#x2013;141.</para>
    <para>Rothstein, J. M. (2004). College performance predictions and the SAT. <emphasis effect="italics">Journal of Econometrics, 121</emphasis>, 297&#x2013;317.</para>
    <para>Rotton, J., &amp; Kelly, I. W. (1985). Much ado about the full moon: A meta-analysis of lunar-lunacy research. <emphasis effect="italics">Psychological Bulletin, 97</emphasis>(2), 286&#x2013;306. doi:10.1037/0033-2909.97.2.286</para>
    <para>Santelices, M. V., &amp; Wilson, M. (2010). Unfair treatment? The case of Freedle, the SAT, and the standardization approach to differential item functioning. <emphasis effect="italics">Harvard Education Review, 80</emphasis>, 106&#x2013;134.</para>
    <para>Sears, D. O. (1986). College sophomores in the laboratory: Influences of a narrow data base on social psychology&#x2019;s view of human nature. <emphasis effect="italics">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology, 51</emphasis>, 515&#x2013;530.</para>
    <para>Shaw, Ch., M., Tan, S. A. (2015). ntegration of Mobile Technology in Educational Materials Improves Participation: Creation of a Novel Smartphone Application for Resident Education. Journal of Surgical Education 72, 670 - 673.</para>
    <para>Shrout, P. E, Rodgers, J. L. (2018). Psychology, Science, and Knowledge Construction: Broadening Perspectives From the Replication Crisis. Annual Review of Psychology, 4, 487-510.</para>
    <para>Tuskegee University. (n.d.). <emphasis effect="italics">About the USPHS Syphilis Study</emphasis>. Retrieved from http://www.tuskegee.edu/about_us/centers_of_excellence/bioethics_center/about_the_usphs_syphilis_study.aspx.</para>
    <para>&#x17B;ukowski, &#x141;. (2017). Etyczne i prawne aspekty dopuszczalno&#x15B;ci przeprowadzania do&#x15B;wiadcze&#x144; na zwierz&#x119;tach. Przegl&#x105;d Prawa i Administracji, Tom 108: Prawna ochrona zwierz&#x105;t, 141 - 156.</para>
  </section>
  <!-- END:Page -->
  <!-- END:Chapter -->
</hack-root>
